

Europass Curriculum Vitae

My LinkedIN profile





Personal information

Surname / First name

Address

C33

Telephone

Personal Email

0.00..a. =...a.

Nationality

Date of birth

Gender

Bio

Buracchi Marco

95, Via Pier Capponi, 50132, Firenze (FI), Italy

+39 3498362954

Personal: ma.buracchi@gmail.com PEC: marco.buracchi@postecert.it

19/12/1985

Male

Italian

I'm an ICS CyberSecurity Specialist at H-ON Consulting in Prato and I attend the Short Specialisation Programme (Master I livello) in Cybersecurity at the Pisa University. I graduated in October 2018 with 110/110 cum laude at the master's degree in computer science, "resilient and secure cyber physical systems" curricula. My master thesis was on "Side-Channel Attacks and speculative execution". Before, I obtained the bachelor degree in computer science in 2015 with 110/110 cum laude.

Desired employment/ Occupational field

IT/OT/IoT security, Software Development & Research

Education and training

Dates

02/2019 - 03/2020 (expected)

Title of qualification awarded

Principal subjects

Short Specialisation Programme - Master I livello in cybersecurity
Applied Cryptography and Access Control, Network Security & Ethical hacking, Op-

erating Systems Security, Digital Forensics, Cyber Intelligence, Mobile and cloud security, Legal aspects of cybersecurity, Secure system configuration, device hardening and firewall management, Risk monitoring for networks and applications, Secure application development (network, mobile, cloud)

Occupational skills covered Expert in security analysis

7

Expert in security analysis of applications and IT systems, expert in cyber attacks analysis

Organization University of Pisa, Department of Information Engineering

CNR (Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche) - Institute of Informatics and Telematics

ISCED/EQF level

Dates

01/10/2015 - 12/10/2018

Title of qualification awarded

Master's degree (Laurea Magistrale) in Resilient and Secure Cyber Physical Systems

Principal subjects/Occupational skills covered Security engineering, Security and network management, Distributed programming for IoT, Multivariate analysis and statistical learning, Coding theory and computer security, Advanced techniques (and tools) for software development, Advanced topics in programming languages, Computer forensics, Models of sequential and concurrent systems, Quantitative analysis of systems, Real-time and critical systems, Systems modeling for verification, Advanced numerical analysis

Organization Final grade ISCED/EQF level University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

110/110 cum laude

7

Dates

08/08/2017 - 12/08/2017

Title of qualification awarded Principal subjects/Occupational Cornell, Maryland, Max Planck pre-doctoral research school

skills covered

Security and privacy, social systems, distributed systems, machine learning, programming languages, and verification

Organization

Max Planck institute for software systems, Cornell University, University of Maryland

Dates

01/10/2012 - 09/10/2015

Title of qualification awarded

Bachelor's Degree (Laurea Triennale) in Computer Science.

Organization

University of Florence, Faculty of Maths, Physics and Natural Sciences

Final grade ISCED/EQF level 110/110 cum laude 6

Work experiences

Dates

13/02/2020 - now

Occupation or position held Main activities ICS CyberSecurity Specialist

Cybersecurity consultancy applied to the OT / IACS world in accordance with the processes and requirements of the IEC 62443 standard, development of services and techniques for the analysis of customer systems in terms of infrastructure and vulnerability, risk analysis, development of specific technical reports, procedures, the choice of necessary HW and SW and the setting up of a new dedicated laboratory. Identifying and coordinating a team of technicians dedicated to the service.

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector H-ON consulting, Via Lepanto, 23, 59100 Prato PO

ICS CyberSecurity

Dates

01/10/2019 - now

Occupation or position held

Junior Security Engineer

Main activities

Vulnerability assessment, penetration testing, research and development.

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector

Florence Consulting Group, Via Luciano Lama, 23, 50019 Sesto Fiorentino Fl

IT Security

Dates

28/11/2018 - 31/08/2019

Occupation or position held

Private tutor

Main activities

One-on-one in-house tutoring for middle-school, high-scool and university students.

Name and address of employer

Centro didattico Matemagia - Via Baracca 166, Firenze

Private education Type of business or sector

Dates

01/04/2015 - 01/10/2016

Occupation or position held

Research helper

Main activities and responsibilities

I took part in AMADEOS project (Architecture for Multi-criticality Agile Dependable Evolutionary Open System-of-Systems) funded under the European Commission's FP7, supporting research in definition, implementation and evaluation of mechanisms and solutions for the resilient management of the time in the smart grid and smart cities. http://amadeos-project.eu/

Name and address of employer Type of business or sector Prof. Andrea Bondavalli, Resilient Computing Lab, Università di Firenze Research and experimentation of dependable architectures and systems Dates

Occupation or position held

Main activities

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

Dates

Occupation or position held

Main activities and

responsibilities

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

01/05/2006 - 01/09/2012

CNC Machinist and Programmer

AutoCAD drawing, CNC programming and cutting (laser cutting, machining center, wire EDM)

Nuova 230AR, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2006 - 01/05/2008)

Gabry packing, Arezzo, Italy (01/05/2008 - 01/09/2012)

Manufacturing industry

tes 01/0

01/09/2004 - 01/05/2006

Technical employee

Direct measurement in field, fixture designer, autoCAD drawing, cutting programs

developer

Emmedi srl, Arezzo, Italy

Manufacturing industry

Personal skills and competences

Mother tongue
Other language(s)
Self-assessment
European level(*)

English

Computer skills and competences

Artistic skills and competences

Driving licence(s)

Italian

| | Understanding | | | Speaking | | | Writing | | |
|----|-------------------|----|-----------------|--------------------|-----------------|-------------------|-----------------|----|-----------------|
| I | Listening Reading | | Reading | Spoken interaction | | Spoken production | | | |
| C1 | Proficient user | C1 | Proficient user | C1 | Proficient user | C1 | Proficient user | C1 | Proficient user |

^(*) Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

knowledge in the use of Kali Linux OS and various IT security and cyber intelligence tools (among the best known: Metasploit, OpenVAS, Nessus, Legion, Maltego). High expertise with many tools such as Apache NiFi, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Maven, Github, virtualization tools, Docker, test-framework.

Very good computer skills, learned as self-taught and through the University. Good

I studied piano at conservatoire for 4 years. I can play guitar. I love skiing and I'm a futsal goalkeeper for more than 10 years

Driver's license (Italian Republic, full European validity), category A (motorcycle owner) and B (car owner).

Additional informations

References

Prof. Michele Boreale, University of Florence, Italy, michele.boreale(AT)unifi.it; Prof. Rosario Pugliese, University of Florence, Italy, rosario.pugliese(AT)unifi.it;

Personal interests

IT security, Technology, Mathematics, Physics and Science in general. Books, Music and all kind of sports. Travelling around the world.

I hereby authorize the processing of the personal data contained in this CV in compliance with the Italian Personal Data Protection Code (Legislative Decree no. 196 of 30 June 2003 and GDPR 679/16 art.13)

Signature:

Home Fundi